Guide to the Carl L. Withers Manuscript Collection RISM.MC.1
New York University Archives
Carl L. Withers Manuscript Collection
1947-2005
New York University Archives
Withers, Carl
RISM.MC.1
16.4 Linear Feet
The Carl L. Withers Manuscript Collection documents the professional career of Carl L. Withers, including his experience as a professor of English, a book editor, anthropologist, and author of works exploring children's folklore. The collection primarily consists of material in English and Spanish that relates to extensive fieldwork studies conducted in various provinces of Cuba between 1947 and 1950. The collection includes correspondence, field notes, children's artwork, folklore, unpublished manuscripts, and an extensive range of black and white photographs. A portion of the collection relates to a research project on student life conducted at Yale University and a pilot study of American teen culture for the U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. Appended items to the collection include correspondence between Dr. Vera D. Rubin and Carl Withers, his bequest of the Cuban materials to Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM), an unpublished memoir written by his friends, and books from his library.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access for some materials. Please contact New York University Archives, (212) 998-2641, university-archives@nyu.edu.
Biographical Note
Carl Loraine Withers was born on March 20, 1900, the youngest of five children. His parents, Sarah Virginia Adams Withers and Horace Smith Withers, settled in a small rural community near Sheldon, Missouri. During his formative years, Withers' family experienced economic hardship. Nevertheless, in 1918 they managed to raise sufficient funds for Withers to travel to Harvard University where he successfuly passed the entrance exam and received conditional acceptance as an English major. For unknown reasons, Withers withdrew from Harvard a year later and for a brief period worked as a field-hand in Ely, Nevada. In 1920 he returned to Harvard to complete his studies and graduated magna cum laude in 1922.
Following graduation, Carl Withers was associated with various academic institutions. In 1923 he taught English at Northwestern University followed by a brief teaching assignment at the College of William and Mary. In 1925 Withers was appointed director of the English Department at Deerfield Academy. He left the position after receiving a fellowship from the Scandinavian-American Foundation at the University of Copenhagen. Over the next two years he traveled and studied in Europe. When he returned to the U.S. in January 1927, he held two part-time teaching positions at New York University (Washington Square College) and the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York.
In 1929, Withers left academia to work as an editor for the Grolier Society in Kansas City, Kansas. This editorial position was the first of several positions he held with the company. While employed by Grolier, Withers acquired knowledge of anthropology through the influential works of A.L. Kroeber and Charles W. Wagley. In 1935 he enrolled in Columbia University's graduate anthropology program. Four years later he secured financial grants that enabled him to conduct a field study in Wheatland, Missouri. Following completion of the project in 1940, and prior to the publication of his findings, Withers resumed teaching at Brooklyn College. His findings were published in 1945 as Plainville, U.S.A. under the pseudonym James West.
In 1947 Withers returned to the Grolier Society's New York office as an editor-in-chief. His major accomplishment during this period was the publication of a ten-volume reference work Lands and Peoples, specifically created for young adults. Withers' second major accomplishment that year involved a successful proposal to conduct field studies in Cuba. Under the auspices of the Viking Fund and the American Philosophical Society, he traveled to Cuba in the summer of 1948, visiting both Mayajigua, Los Villas, situated on the north central coast of Cuba, and Trinidad, a city in central Cuba noted for its colonial architecture.
In the fall of 1948, Withers returned to the U.S. and accepted the position of Research Associate at Yale University's Department of Student Health. Working with Ralph Linton, his former graduate advisor at Columbia University, Withers organized studies focusing on the psychological stress experienced by undergraduates. The resulting publication, which Withers co-authored with Abram Kardiner, Ralph Linton, and Cora Du Bois, was published as Psychological Frontiers of Society.
Between 1949 and 1950, Withers returned to Mayajigua and expanded his field studies to include several other regions. He returned to the U.S. in 1950, intent on organizing the Cuban materials for publication. However, in 1952, a grant from the American International Association allowed him to travel to Venezuela, where he taught vocational skills in select schools for a year. In 1953 Withers accepted the position of visiting professor at the University of Brazil. While there, he conducted a field study of Arraial do Cabo, a coastal fishing village, as part of field work training for the employees of the National Museum of Brazil.
In 1956 Withers received a grant from the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) to complete the Cuban manuscript, but after three years the work was still incomplete. In 1959 he accepted the position of Social Science Research Analyst at the Children's Bureau of the U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare (DHEW). In September 1960, with the financial support of DHEW and additional grants from the Ford Foundation and RISM, Withers launched a pilot study on American teen culture in St. Louis, Missouri. Through an arrangement with DHEW, Withers served as a visiting professor at Washington University in Missouri for the length of the study.
In the final years of his life, Carl Withers' long-standing interest in children's folklore dominated his time. His first book in the genre was the classic Rocket in My Pocket, published in 1948. By the mid-1960s 70,000 copies of the book had been sold.
In 1969 Withers' health began to decline, prompting his decision to transfer the Cuban materials to RISM. He died of a stroke in his Greenwich Village home on January 5, 1970.
Sources:
Jablow, Joseph. "Carl Withers." American Anthropologist. 74 (1973): 764-769.
Hopkins, Frank Snowden. Carl Withers, A Memoir for his friends. August 1972 [unpublished manuscript]
Scope and Contents
The Carl L. Withers Manuscript Collection chronicles Withers' fieldwork studies conducted in Cuba during the mid 20th century and includes correspondence, stenographic notebooks used for fieldwork entries, folklore, observations and research citations, print material, children's art work, poems and essays, unpublished manuscripts, photographs, maps, and ephemera.
Major strengths of the collection include more than 1,000 black and white photographs, which offer a rare portrait of Cuba during the pre-Castro era. Although Withers documented his 1948 visits to Mayajigua (Los Villas) and Trinidad, as well as subsequent visits in 1949 and 1950 to Havana, it remains unclear when he visited Baracoa, Santiago, Camaguey and other regions where photographs were taken.
There are also many challenges associated with the collection. Much of the correspondence is riddled with abbreviations and anthropological symbols, typical of Withers' handwriting. Many of the photographs lack identifying information. In addition, several of the photographs have been marred by Withers' handwritten notations.
Unpublished manuscripts include fragile and brittle papers that have been photocopied for research purposes.
The collection has benefited from a number of appended items that provide additional insight into Withers' life and particularly his working relationship with Dr. Vera D. Rubin and others. Culled from RISM's institutional files, these items include: 1) Withers' book proposal and outline for the Cuban study entitled The Green Island: Life in a Cuban Town, 2) select correspondence between Withers and Dr. Rubin concerning grants for the Cuban Study and the American Youth Culture Project, subsequently published as Plainville U.S.A., and a book review, 3) samples of a survey used to collect children's folklore, 4) Carl Withers' bequest to the Research Institute for the Study of Man, 5) a memoir written by Frank Snowden Hopkins, which includes Xeroxed images of Withers, 6) an obituary published in the American Anthropologist in 1972, and 7) posthumous correspondence related to Withers' Cuban materials.
Arrangement
The Carl L. Withers Collection has been organized chronologically within each series.
The collection is arranged is in the following series:
I. Correspondence
II. Notes on Cuba [Field Journals]
III. Children's Artwork and Writings
IV. Folklore Collection
V. Photograph Collection
VI. Unpublished Manuscripts
VII. Studies in American Youth Culture
VIII. Personal Writings
IX. Oversized materials
X. Material from Frank Snowden Hopkins
XI. AV Materials (Material from Jorge Giovanetti)
XII. Marcos A. Iglesias' Volumes on Yaguajay, Cuba
Appendix
Related Material
The Sula Benet Papers, RISM RG 2.
Separated Material
Envelopes with rare stamps have been separated from the collection and placed in the ALS/TLS section of the finding aid binder.
Books, journals, and other publications from the estate of Carl Withers, via the Research Institute for the Study of Man, were cataloged and are searchable in BobCat.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were given to University Archives over several years by RISM, Withers, and others close to him.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use preservation copies of manuscripts in Series VI.
Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Havana (Cuba); Camagüey (Cuba).; Anthropology.; Correspondence.; Notebooks; New York (N.Y.).; Baracoa (Cuba: Municipio).; Postcards.; Cuba -- Literatures; Youth -- North America; Trinidad (Cuba: Municipio); Cuba -- History.; Brazil.; Manuscripts; Venezuela.; Wagley, Charles, 1913-1991; College of William & Mary; Rubin, Vera D.; Brooklyn College. Faculty; Benet, Sula, 1903-1982; Washington Square College; United States. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; Linton, Ralph, 1893-1953
- Series I. Correspondence
  Scope and Contents Note
  5 folders, arranged chronologically. This series mainly consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence between Carl Withers and his field informants, Juan Benito Orosa and Manuel Picabea. The majority of letters are written in Spanish, and a few include adivinanzas (riddles) and cuentos (stories). Some ephemera is also included.
  - Addendum: Correspondence between Carl Withers & Ruth Benedict, 31 July 1943 to 25 Sept. 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, ephemera, Aug 1948 - Dec 1948, Aug 1949 - Jan 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Nov 1952, Aug 1955 - Sep 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, ephemera, Aug 1956 - Dec 1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1957 - May 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II. Notes on Cuba [Field Journals]
  0.5 linear feet, arranged chronologically. This series consists of 18 stenographic notebooks that contain observations, pencil drawings, anecdotes, folklore, and research citations recorded by Carl Withers while conducting field studies in Mayajigua (Los Villas), Cuba. Although the notebooks are not in strict chronological order, the numbers assigned by Withers have been retained. An index of subject content for all notebooks can be found in Box 2, folder 9.
  - Cuba 1, Nov 1947 - Jan 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cuba 2, Jan 1948 - Feb 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cuba 3, Feb 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cuba 4, Feb 1948 - Mar 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cuba 5, Mar 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cuba 1, Mar 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cuba 6, Mar 1948 - Aug 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cuba 2, May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cuba 3, May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cuban Riddles, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cuba 7, Jun 1948 - Jul 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Teresa I, Jul 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Teresa II, July 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cuba 8, Jul 1948 - Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cuba 9, Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cuba 10, Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cuba 11, Aug 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cuba 12, Aug 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Index to Notebooks, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series III. Children's Artwork and Writings
  0.5 linear feet, arranged chronologically. This series includes artwork, handwritten poems, and essays. The material appears to have been gathered by Carl Withers with the assistance of his field informant Juan Benito Orosa.
  - Cuaderno de Dibujo [notebook], Mar 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pencil drawing of fish and a horse, Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pencil drawing of three figures, poem at bottom, Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pencil drawing of a boy, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pencil and crayon drawing of a plane or rocket, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pencil and crayon drawing of boy, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Color pencil drawing of a palm tree, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Color pencil drawing of a tree, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - List of colors written in color pencil, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Circle drawn in color pencil, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pencil drawing of house and trees, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Color pencil drawing of house, picket fence, and boy climbing a tree, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series IV. Folklore Collection
  Approximately 1.0 linear feet, arranged chronologically. This series includes typescript and handwritten poems, unpublished essays, and manuscripts. Although written in Spanish, these documents have been extensively annotated by Carl Withers in English. The series also includes print material, invitations, research notes, and ephemera, as well as a number of undated notebooks, some titled, that contain citations, notes and stories.
  - Poetry, manuscripts, print material, notes, ephemera, May 1948 - Aug 1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wedding invitation, sketches, map and manuscript, notes, ephemera, Jul 1948 - Aug 1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, manuscripts, Sep 1948 - Nov 1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts, 1948 - 1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts, 1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Print material, poetry, manuscript, invitations, notes, Jul 1949 - Aug 1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Unpublished manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts, notes, reprint of the article "Courtship in Granada Spain," from Atlantic Monthly, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Folktales: L.C I. [Library of Congress], undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Folktales L.C. II., undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Formula (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Untitled notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Untitled notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newell, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Questions and notes re: writings of L.R. + M.P. [Manuel Picabea], undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - JAFL 1 [Journal of American Folklore], undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Strange II, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Strange 31 [cover missing], undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series V. Photographs, 1947-1950
  Photographs arranged by region, group, and photo number. This series contains approximately 1044 black and white photos taken during Withers' field studies in Cuba between 1947 - 1950. It is organized into five subseries: Mayajigua, Trinidad, Baracoa, Camaguey, Habana and Havana, and scanned and unidentified photos. Withers' photo captions, identification of camera used, (i.e. Bantam BN), and numbering system were recorded on storage envelopes and are included below. Items that were present in Wither's numbering system but were missing from the collection are also listed. The envelopes have been placed at the end of each photo group. Added captions, photo numbers, clarification of symbols, and translation of some Spanish words and phrases appear in brackets.
  - Subseries A. Mayajigua (Box 5)
    - Group 1
      - [Man stands in the foreground; church in the background], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-1-1)
      - [Group of children with bicycles], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-1-14)
      - [Group of men pose outside building] "Roberto" written on back, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-1-?)
    - Group 1 [BN]
      - Ulise Perez - [girlfriend] of Branlio[Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 1)
      - Lake and plane at baño, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 2)
      - Airport, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 3)
      - Airport, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 4)
      - Bonza's nephew and Novia, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 5)
      - Guests of baño ("Tulito, Georgie," written on back of photo), 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 6)
      - Plane, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 7)
      - [No photograph], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN1 - 8)
    - Group 2
      - Café Europa, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 1)
      - St. Baratillo - Hotel Jara - Robert, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 2)
      - Indoors - men sitting around, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 3)
      - [No comments or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 4)
      - Digging stump: Jose Luis Garcia's house plot, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 5)
      - Little girls in st. [street], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 6)
      - Cil at house, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 7)
      - Veterano + w. [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 8)
      - Horse tethered at bodega of Chinito's [friend?], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 9)
      - The delap'd [dilapidated] house across patio - hotel, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -10)
      - The patio, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -11)
      - Tio, Pedro + Cil in upstairs corridor, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -12)
      - Entierrito (little funeral), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -13)
      - Same as M2 - 13, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -14)
      - Hotel Comercio: Yaguajay, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -15)
      - Hotel Comercio: Yaguajay, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -16)
      - [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -17)
      - [Note: Number "19" is crossed out and "18" substituted -- should read Cil [children game Yaguajay?], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -18)
      - [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -19)
      - [Note "18" crossed out and "20" substituted. Caption should read: Ice cream wagon: Yaguajay], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 - 20)
      - Roberto + Julito (corner of Baratillo), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -21)
      - Roberto + Julito (corner of Baratillo), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -22)
      - [Children] at home of Dona Maria (?), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -23)
      - [Children] at home of Dona Maria (?), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -24)
      - Julito's little sister, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -25)
      - The wedding porch [out of focus], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -26)
      - The wedding porch [out of focus], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -27)
      - [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-2 -28)
    - Group 3 [BN]
      - Crowd on porch at wedding, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 1)
      - Church with buzzard on cross, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 2)
      - Same [as above], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 3)
      - M. + S.; mare + colt (front of Covadenga), 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 4)
      - Pig + barrel (Cobad. Upstairs), 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 5)
      - Eberto - Cobado porch, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 6)
      - Boy - sitio bonito, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 7)
      - The 3 horses of Alfredo Soccoros' dibujo [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-3 - 8)
    - Group 3
      - Little Juarez w. stickhorse (Roberto, Jorge et al), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 1)
      - Little Juarez w. stickhorse (Roberto, Jorge et al), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 2)
      - Carpenters working, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 3)
      - Bonza's Novia teaching at sister's house, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 4)
      - Woman washing in batea (in town?), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 5)
      - Naked child - palm log - thatch'd roof (for photos 5 and 6 Withers notes "these in extreme sw of pueblo"), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 6)
      - Mare and colt, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 7)
      - Mare and colt, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 8)
      - Dona Amalie's home, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 9)
      - Dona Amalie's home, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 10)
      - Distant [view of] mule team Withers note: "was getting shine at Europa", 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 11)
      - Child playing on great cowhide, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 12)
      - Mare and colt in hotel patio, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 13)
      - [S.O. upstairs at hotel. Teo?] [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 14)
      - Same as photo M-3 - 13, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 15)
      - Child in door (in patio), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 16)
      - Little girl and mulatto zapatere's smallest boy, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 17)
      - Street scene: guano, palmas, etc., 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 18)
      - 2 cil [children] playing by river, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 19)
      - [girls] hanging out wash, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 20)
      - [woman] carrying [child] other [child] hides; downtown, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 21)
      - Crowd walking [to] r.r., 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 22)
      - [No comment or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 23)
      - [girls shopping in botica] [botanica?] [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-3 - 24)
    - Group 4 [BN]
      - M.P. [Manuel Picabea] + Luisito, sitting in front of Rancho Grande, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 1)
      - [No comments or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 2)
      - [No comments or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 3)
      - babneario carpenter (Negro) in shop, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 4)
      - [chair - baño carpenteria?] [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 5)
      - Negro boy - cross-striped sweatshirt, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 6)
      - Muddy baño road, walkers + horsemen, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 7)
      - f + s [father and son] horseback - muddy baño road, 1948 (Box 5, Object BN-4 - 8)
    - Group 4
      - Corner of Louvre (town, carts, people, etc.), 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 1)
      - [Man] sweeping sidewalk, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 2)
      - M.P. [Manuel Picabea] passing parked station wagon, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 3)
      - Negrito carrying parcels on sidewalk, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 4)
      - Horseman leading pack horse in [street], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 5)
      - Negro boy with cocky straw hat, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 6)
      - A backyard, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 7)
      - Clothes drying, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 8)
      - [No comment or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 9)
      - Butcher shop, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 10)
      - Man at door talking to housewife, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 11)
      - [women] and [children] posed on porch [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 12)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 13)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 14)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4- 15)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 16)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 17)
      - Wedding [Missing], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 18)
      - [No comment or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4 - 19)
      - No comment or photo], 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4- 20)
      - (--negative) Little mulatto girl walking on street, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-4- 21)
        General note
        [Note on storage envelope: + Negs (3) Winter trip (- pictures). Envelope also includes several unidentified photos]
    - Group 5
      - [Children] and house: Road to Perea, 1948 (Box 5, Object M-5 - 1)